Guide to the Duke Real Estate Office records, 1893-2018 and undated UA.10.04.0007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Real Estate Deeds, 1893-2018; undated
  - File No.: 2336, Grantee: Urs and Arianne Pohlman, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settlement, deed, 2001 May 31 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3100, Page: 677, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 11, Comments/Location: 848 Sedgefield Street
  - File No.: 2337, Grantee: John and Sue Willis, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settlement, deed, 2001 June 22 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3123, Page: 999, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesites lot 22, Comments/Location: 805 Berkeley Street
  - File No.: 2338, Grantee: John Little and Elizabeth W., Grantor: Duke University, Type: settlement, deed, 2001 May 30 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3100, Page: 705, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 10, Comments/Location: 844 Sedgefield Street
  - File No.: 2339, Grantee: John Transue and Kirsten, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle., deed, 2001 July 26 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3158, Page: 243, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 7, Comments/Location: 820 Sedgefield Street
  - File No.: 2340, Grantee: Fred Dietrich, Grantor: Duke University, Type: Settle., deed, 2001 July 31 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3162, Page: 562, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 5, Comments/Location: 831 Sedgefield Street
  - File No.: 2341, Grantee: Sally Kornbluth and Daniel Lew, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle.,deed, 2001 September 25 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3213, Page: 207, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 4, Comments/Location: 835 Sedgefield Street
  - File No.: 2342, Grantee: Elisabeth and William Stagg, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 September 14 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3204, Page: 257, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 2, Comments/Location: 851 Sedgefield Street
  - File No.: 2343, Grantee: Robert Healy and Kay Edgar, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 October 25
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3240, Page: 905-908, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 3, Comments/Location: 839 Sedgefield Street
  - File No.: 2344, Grantee: Jim and Andrea Manson, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 November 13 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3261, Page: 353, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 21, Comments/Location: 807 Berkeley Street
  - File No.: 2345, Grantee: Tom and Sarah Mustillo, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 November 16 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3266, Page: 444, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 5-A, Comments/Location: 812 Onslow Street
  - File No.: 2346, Grantee: David and Beverly Markham, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 December 19 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3303, Page: 97, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. New Homesite lot 12, Comments/Location: 842 Sedgefield Street
  - File No.: 2347, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Gattis and Graham, Type: settle, title ins, deed, 2002 May 3 (Box 28)
    County: Orange, Deed Book: 2581, Page: 371, Comments/Location: 8.966 acres (Duke Forest) off Ben Johnson Rd.
  - File No.: 2348, Grantee: Fred and Jane Raimi, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 August 14 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3179, Page: 329, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 38, Comments/Location: 1502 W. Markham
  - File No.: 2349, Grantee: Jacqueline Ariail, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 August 22 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3181, Page: 145, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 30, Comments/Location: 802 Sedgefield St.
  - File No.: 2350, Grantee: Helen Chandler, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 August 23 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3182, Page: 134, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 27, Comments/Location: 808 Sedgefield St.
  - File No.: 2351, Grantee: Adrian Hernandez, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 August 24 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3184, Page: 578, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 29, Comments/Location: 804 Sedgefield St.
  - File No.: 2352, Grantee: Edward Suarez, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 August 31 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3192, Page: 880, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 28, Comments/Location: 806 Sedgefield St.
  - File No.: 2353, Grantee: Laura Helton, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 August 31 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3192, Page: 869, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 25, Comments/Location: 812 Sedgefield St.
  - File No.: 2354, Grantee: Elizabeth Cavanaugh, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 September 13 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3202, Page: 860, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 32, Comments/Location: 1514 W. Markham
  - File No.: 2355, Grantee: Peter and Katherine Malin, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 November 9 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3257, Page: 196, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 31, Comments/Location: 1516 W. Markham Ave.
  - File No.: 2356, Grantee: Gregory Rives, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 December 20 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3306, Page: 593, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 33, Comments/Location: 1512 W. Markham Ave.
  - File No.: 2357, Grantee: Lynn Alexander & Peter Krause, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2001 December 21 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3306, Page: 256, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 24, Comments/Location: 814 Sedgefield St.
  - File No.: 2358, Grantee: Therese Hennig & husband, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2002 March 27 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 37, Comments/Location: 1504 W. Markham Ave.
  - File No.: 2359, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Bobby Levy and Stephanie, Type: title insurance, 2002 May 20 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3447, Page: 847-849, Map-Block-Lot: Phase one buyback, Comments/Location: 817 Lancaster street
  - File No.: 2360, Grantee: DUHS/RCH, Grantor: ROCDOCS, Type: deed, offer, 2003 June 1 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 10188, Page: 139-141, Map-Block-Lot: RCH purchase, Comments/Location: 3320 Wake Forest Rd, Unit 120, Raleigh
  - File No.: 2361, Grantee: High Point Realty Assoc, Inc, Grantor: Duke Special Ventures Fund, Inc, Type: agree, note, 2001 June 30 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: Washington Duke Inn, Comments/Location: Special ventures to High Point Realty
  - File No.: 2361.1, Grantee: Washington Duke Inn, LLC, Grantor: Margot Realty (nominee), Type: deed copy, 2002 June 28 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3490, Page: 800-803, Map-Block-Lot: Washington Duke Inn, Comments/Location: Margot Realty (as nominee) to WDI, LLC
  - File No.: 2362, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Frank and Louise Chut, Type: deed, 2002 June 20 (Box 28)
    County: Carteret, Deed Book: 945, Page: 622, Map-Block-Lot: Lots 41, 42, 43 Magens Bay, Comments/Location: 11,112, 113 Magen Court Swansboro, NC
  - File No.: 2363, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: J. C. Jessup, Type: deed, 2002 June 3 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3463, Page: 695-698, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 103 Treyburn, Comments/Location: Treyburn Country Club Villa
  - File No.: 2364, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Warren and Mary Barker, Type: deed, 2002 April 12 (Box 28)
    County: Tehama, CA, Deed Book: 2148, Page: 279, Map-Block-Lot: APN 009-300-9-12, Comments/Location: Tehama Co., California undeveloped riverfront lot
  - File No.: 2365, Grantee: Eckenwiler and Prassa, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, 2002 June 20 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: E. C. Homesite Lot, Comments/Location: 821 Lancaster Street
  - File No.: 2366, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Kathy Pories, Mark Johnson, Type: settle, deed, 2002 August 8 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3532, Page: 630-632, Map-Block-Lot: Phase one Trinity Heights, Comments/Location: 813 Onslow Street
  - File No.: 2366.1, Grantee: Jane and Greg Bell, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed copy, 2003 October 23 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4156, Page: 579-582, Map-Block-Lot: Phase OneTrinity Heights, Comments/Location: 813 Onslow
  - File No.: 2367, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Philip Benfey, Type: promiss. note, 2002 August 28 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: 307 Hillsboro Street, Chapel Hill, Comments/Location: certification, promissory, deed of release
  - File No.: 2368, Grantee: Hock Family LLC, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2002 August 30 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3557, Page: 312-314, Map-Block-Lot: Douglas and Pratt Streets, Comments/Location: Nearly New Shop; deal inc lease at Hock Plaza
  - File No.: 2369, Grantee: Scott Kollins, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2002 April 24 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. townhouse, Comments/Location: 1508 W. Markham
  - File No.: 2370, Grantee: Chad and Catherine Harness, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2002 May 15 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: E.C. Homesite Lot 1, Comments/Location: 855 Sedgefield St.
  - File No.: 2371, Grantee: John Utz and Laura Hall, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2002 June 12 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: E. C. additional lot, Comments/Location: 1409 Green Street
  - File No.: 2372, Grantee: Catholic Diocese, Grantor: Duke University, Type: Settle, deed, 2002 September 10 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: 402 N. Buchanan, Comments/Location: Rhine Institute for Newman Catholic Center, Old/New File No.: 2298
  - File No.: 2373, Grantee: Powers, Victor and wife, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, 2003 April 24 (Box 28)
    County: Chatham, Deed Book: 1014, Page: 515-16, Map-Block-Lot: 816 and 817 Glenn Glade, Comments/Location: two of four lots in Govs Club: FREY gift
  - File No.: 2374, Grantee: Vance Tucker, Grantor: Duke University, Type: option, 2003 May 5 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: 7 acre tract Duke Forest, Comments/Location: Durham Co. Tax map 760-001-04
  - File No.: 2375, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Dr. Angus McBryde, Type: deed (gift), 2002 December 24 (Box 28)
    County: Henderson, Deed Book: 1123, Page: 615, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 25 White's Lake, Saluda, Comments/Location: Tax map ref 9596-15-0630-55
  - File No.: 2375.1, Grantee: Gordon and Martha Schneider, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2003 June 19 (Box 28)
    County: Henderson, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 25 White's Lake, Saluda, Comments/Location: Tax map ref 9596-15-0630-55
  - File No.: 2376, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Dr. Angus McBryde, Type: deed (gift), 2002 December 24 (Box 28)
    County: McDowell, Deed Book: 712, Page: 820, Map-Block-Lot: B173, 817 Wildflower Lane, Comments/Location: Tax map ref 0656.00-89-1676
  - File No.: 2377, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Gertrude Mayo, Type: settle, title ins., 2003 September 24 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4119, Page: 513-516, Map-Block-Lot: 1408 Faber Street, Comments/Location: across from Center for Jewish Life
  - File No.: 2378, Grantee: Cellco d.b.a. Verizon Wireless, Grantor: Duke University, Type: mem. lease, 2002 December 20 (Box 28)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 3701, Page: 826-831, Map-Block-Lot: 0811-11-66-2281, Comments/Location: cell tower site license
  - File No.: 2379, Grantee: Duke Univ Health Systems, Grantor: Roi Ngo, Jessica Ngo, Type: Title, ins, settle, 2003 November 14 (Box 28)
    County: Wake, Deed Book: 10545, Page: 2269-71, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 12 Block A, Comments/Location: 1309 Ingomar Place
  - File No.: 2380, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Dr. Lynn George and wife, Ruth, Type: Deed, 2003 November 4 (Box 29)
    County: Moore, Deed Book: 2431, Page: 573-575, Comments/Location: 160 E. Shenandoah Rd. West End, NC
  - File No.: 2381, Grantee: Shanley LLC- Lestini, Grantor: Duke University, Type: Deed, settle., 2003 December 4 (Box 29)
    County: Wake, Comments/Location: 3320 Wake Forest Rd. Suite 430
  - File No.: 2382, Grantee: Dr. Forsyth, Grantor: DUHS, Type: lease amend., 2003 December 30 (Box 29)
    County: Wake, Deed Book: 10611, Page: 122-124, Comments/Location: 3320 Wake Forest Rd suites 400-413, 490-503 RCH
  - File No.: 2383, Grantee: Durham Realty, Inc, Grantor: nuBridges, LLC, Type: stock cert., 2003 December 31 (Box 29)
    County: Georgia, Comments/Location: 150,000 shares
  - File No.: 2384, Grantee: Dr. Carr, Grantor: DUHS, Type: deed, 2004 January 9 (Box 29)
    County: Wake, Deed Book: 10656, Page: 2510-13, Comments/Location: Suites 151-175, 326-350, 3400 Executive Drive, RCH
  - File No.: 2385, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Stokes, Type: deed, title ins., 2004 March 15 (Box 29)
    County: Orange, Deed Book: 3368, Page: 549, Comments/Location: 26.712 acres in Orange County (Duke Forest)
  - File No.: 2385.1, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Stokes, Type: deed, title ins., 2004 March 15 (Box 29)
    County: Orange, Deed Book: 3368, Page: 462, Comments/Location: 10 acres in Duke Forest
  - File No.: 2386, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Kirkman, Larry and Martha, Type: deed, title ins., 2004 March 15 (Box 29)
    County: Orange, Deed Book: 3368, Page: 455, Comments/Location: 25.53 acres in Orange county (Duke Forest)
  - File No.: 2387, Grantee: NOAA et al., Grantor: Duke University (forest), Type: license, 2004 March 1 (Box 29)
    County: Orange, Comments/Location: Climate Ref Network Meteorological Station
  - File No.: 2388, Grantee: Duke, Grantor: Richard Palmer, Type: license, 2004 May 6 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: 126 Pinecrest, Comments/Location: gardening agreement in adjacent lot
  - File No.: 2389, Grantee: Schmitt-Grohe and Uribe, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2004 May 11 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4385, Page: 615-619, Map-Block-Lot: recomb. Plat Book 161 Pg 210, Comments/Location: 2240 Cranford, Spengler house
  - File No.: 2390, Grantee: DUHS-RCH, Grantor: Mary M. Kemp, Type: deed, 2004 June 28 (Box 29)
    County: Wake, Deed Book: 10895, Page: 2015-018, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 11, Blk A Greenwood Farms, Comments/Location: 1311 Ingomar St. for RCH
  - File No.: 2391, Grantee: DUHS-RCH, Grantor: Maxine D. Russell, Type: deed, 2004 June 28 (Box 29)
    County: Wake, Deed Book: 10895, Page: 1844-46, Map-Block-Lot: Lot 10, Blk A Sec 2 Greenwood, Comments/Location: 3605 Greenlawn for RCH
  - File No.: 2392, Grantee: Durham Realty Inc, Grantor: Crabtree, Laws, Latta, Type: deed, title insur, 2004 August 24 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4516, Page: 322-325, Comments/Location: 2805 Hillsborough Road
  - File No.: 2393, Grantee: Durham Realty Inc, Grantor: Southgate and Son, Type: deed, title insur, 2004 September 15 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4543, Page: 43927, Map-Block-Lot: Primate Center: Div of Fossil Primates, Comments/Location: 1013 Broad St
  - File No.: 2394, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: George McLendon, Type: deed, title insur, 2004 March 25 (Box 29)
    County: Mercer, Deed Book: 4759, Page: 287, Map-Block-Lot: Princeton deed, Comments/Location: 511 Cherry Hill road (to be sold)
  - File No.: 2395, Grantee: Taylor's Creek Holdings, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, settlement, 2004 December 17 (Box 29)
    County: Carteret, Map-Block-Lot: Colonial Apts, Carpenter cottage, Comments/Location: 121,122,123,125 Front St, Beaufort
  - File No.: 2396, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Mildred Payton, Type: deed, settle, title, 2004 December 20 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4647, Page: 150-153, Map-Block-Lot: 308 Powe Street, Durham, Comments/Location: 308 Powe Street
  - File No.: 2397, Grantee: Duke Gift Properties Inc, Grantor: Williams and Hessee, Type: settle, 2004 December 20 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4647, Page: 617-620, Map-Block-Lot: Campus Arms Apartments, Comments/Location: 2222,2224,2226 Elba/ 2226 Elder streets
  - File No.: 2397.1, Grantee: Ronald McDonald House of Durham, Grantor: Duke Gift Properties Inc, Type: settle, memo, 2004 December 20 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4647, Page: 639-642, Map-Block-Lot: Campus Arms Apartments, Comments/Location: 2222,2224,2226 Elba/ 2226 Elder streets
  - File No.: 2398, Grantee: Duke Gift Properties Inc, Grantor: Eugene McDonald, Type: settle, lease, 2004 December 22 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4652, Page: 344-346, Comments/Location: 201 Villa (Treyburn) leased back
  - File No.: 2399, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Klopfer, Peter/Martha, Type: deed, memo agree, 2004 December 22 (Box 29)
    County: Orange, Deed Book: 3641, Page: 166, Map-Block-Lot: forest acreage/lifetime lease
  - File No.: 2400, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Carolina Friends School, Type: deed, 2004 December 22 (Box 29)
    County: Orange, Deed Book: 3461, Page: 171, Comments/Location: PIN 9891.29.9800
  - File No.: 2401, Grantee: Duke Gift Properties, Inc, Grantor: Mann Realty Assoc, Inc, Type: Stock Certif., 2004 December 30 (Box 29)
    Map-Block-Lot: Stock shares, Comments/Location: Mann Realty Associates, Inc
  - File No.: 2402, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Esther W. Tate, Type: Deed, 2005 February 16 (Box 29)
    County: Orange, Deed Book: 3675, Page: 292, Map-Block-Lot: 19 acres, Comments/Location: Old HWY 86
  - File No.: 2403, Grantee: Flanagan, Owen and spouse, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed cc, 2005 March 28 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: Trinity Heights new, Comments/Location: 817 and 815 Lancaster Street
  - File No.: 2404, Grantee: Durham County, Grantor: Duke University, Type: contract,memorandum, 2005 April 8 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: 42 acre tract off of Erwin Road, Comments/Location: Erwin Trace- county purchase
  - File No.: 2405, Grantee: Anlyan, William, Grantor: Duke University, Type: settle, deed, add., 2005 April 28 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4773, Page: 610, Map-Block-Lot: additional land forest homesite, Comments/Location: Pinecrest lot to build smaller house
  - File No.: 2406, Grantee: Cox, Murray and Deborah, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2005 November 10 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5022, Page: 943, Map-Block-Lot: -381090, Comments/Location: 5708 Prioress Drive (Allen Gift)
  - File No.: 2407, Grantee: Liggett Group, Grantor: Durham Realty, Inc., Type: lease termination, 2006 December 5 (Box 29)
    Deeds in the Real Estate Office are copies of public records, and are open for research. Additional materials under administrative restriction until 2031.
  - File No.: 2408, Grantee: Investors Title Exchange, Grantor: Durham Realty, Inc., Type: promiss. note, 2006 February 27 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: $450k Part of Solie Prop Purchase Price
  - File No.: 2409, Grantee: Beacon Street Bradley, LLC, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2006 April 20 (Box 29)
    County: Carteret, Map-Block-Lot: Beaufort Property, Comments/Location: 103 Moore St, Beaufort NC 28517
  - File No.: 2410, Grantee: Dwayne Huebner & E. Davis, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2007 April 3 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5560, Page: 600-603, Comments/Location: Berkeley St- Trinity Heights
  - File No.: 2411, Grantee: Sam & Jo Wells, Grantor: Durham Realty, Inc., Type: promiss. note, 2007 May 24 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Comments/Location: 704 North Buchanan Blvd.
  - File No.: 2412, Grantee: Orange County, NC, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed & covenants, 2006 February 16 (Box 29)
    County: Orange, Deed Book: 3970, Page: 417
  - File No.: 2414, Grantee: Durham Realty, Inc., Grantor: Soleil, LLC, Type: deed, 2006 February 28 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5126, Page: 678-685
  - File No.: 2415, Grantee: Duke Energy Corp., Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2005 November 10 (Box 29)
  - File No.: 2416, Grantee: Durham Realty, Inc., Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2006 March 2 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5131, Page: 90, Comments/Location: 115 SF, MC Main St Shop
  - File No.: 2417, Grantee: McCracken Family, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2007 September 19 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5746, Page: 832, Comments/Location: trade parcels with McCracken; part of Duke School deal
  - File No.: 2417, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: McCracken Family, Type: deed, 2007 September 19 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5746, Page: 837
  - File No.: 2418, Grantee: Durham Realty, Inc., Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2008 March 10 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5892, Page: 148, Comments/Location: 4 tracts - Maxwell St
  - File No.: 2418, Grantee: Durham Realty, Inc., Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2008 March 10 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5892, Page: 152, Comments/Location: Liggett Smith Storage Building
  - File No.: 2418, Grantee: Durham Realty, Inc., Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2008 March 10 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5892, Page: 155, Comments/Location: Maxwell St
  - File No.: 2419, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Lewis Hawley, Type: deed, 2011 December 2 (Box 29)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 6856, Page: 141, Comments/Location: 402 K Street
  - File No.: 2420, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Robert Phillips Jr, Type: deed, 2010 July 22 (Box 30)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 6524, Page: 83, Comments/Location: W/S 15-501 Bypass, S Moreene Road
  - File No.: 2421, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Madison Washburn Court LLC, Type: deed, 2012 November 21 (Box 30)
    Deeds in the Real Estate Office are copies of public records, and are open for research. Additional materials under administrative restriction until 2037.
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 7124, Page: 928, Comments/Location: 249 SF Gap Margin Hull Avenue
  - File No.: 2422, Grantee: NE Alamance VFD, Grantor: Duke University, Type: deed, 2015 July 10 (Box 30)
    County: Alamance, Deed Book: 3449, Page: 31, Comments/Location: 3.48 acres
  - File No.: 2423, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Blacknall House Partnership, Type: deed, 2011 December 29 (Box 30)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 6875, Page: 691, Comments/Location: 300 Alexander Avenue
  - File No.: 2424, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Durham Realty, Inc, Type: Deed, 2008 March 10 (Box 30)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5892, Page: 152, Comments/Location: Smith Warehouse
- Real Estate Easements, 1912-2006; undated
  Deeds in the Real Estate Office are copies of public records, and are open for research. For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist. Contact Research Services for more information.
  Easements begin with File No. 3000.
  - File No.: 3000, Grantee: City of Durham, Grantor: Duke, Type: Easement, 1953 May 19 (Box 30)
    County: Durham, Map-Block-Lot: Duke Homesites, Comments/Location: Woodburn Rd. & Pickett Rd. sewer outfalls
  - File No.: 3001, Grantee: City of Durham, Grantor: Duke, Type: Deed, 1930 February 13 (Box 30)
    County: Durham, Comments/Location: Main Street & Buchanan Blvd., Old/New File No.: 237
  - File No.: 3002, Grantee: City of Durham, Grantor: Duke, Type: Deed, 1930 August 19 (Box 30)
    County: Durham, Comments/Location: Buchanan & College Road, Old/New File No.: 238
  - File No.: 3003, Grantee: City of Durham, Grantor: Duke, Type: Deed, 1928 November 22 (Box 30)
    County: Durham, Comments/Location: Chapel Hill Street, Old/New File No.: 310
  - File No.: 3004, Grantee: City of Durham, Grantor: Duke, Type: Deed, 1930 November 7 (Box 30)